<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Decompiled</title>
    <link>http://decompiled.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Decompiled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://decompiled.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://decompiled.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://decompiled.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>About Decompiled is dedicated to the public domain. Meaning the work presented at decompiled.dev is as much yours as it is mine. You can do as you wish with it, except claim exclusive ownership.
Obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t grant ownership of other&amp;rsquo;s intellectual property to the public. I may unwittingly repeat something I read without proper citations. Copy freely, at your own risk. The material presented is intended for educational purposes only, and should in no way be construed as advice in any capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halo: The Harbinger of Zero Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://decompiled.dev/crypto/halo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://decompiled.dev/crypto/halo/</guid>
      <description>Cryptography is the science of protecting messages from adversarial threats. It has been used for millennia by those entrusted with secrets of their state. With the rise of e-commerce it has found broad consumer use. Modern cryptography allows us to protect sensitive information transmitted over public networks such as credit card numbers. Advancements made in cryptography serve as the foundation of the digital economy.
Traditionally cryptography has been focused on protecting messages in transit as they travel from an originator to their intended recipient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrix: Own your Chatter</title>
      <link>http://decompiled.dev/matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://decompiled.dev/matrix/</guid>
      <description>Imagine if each email client could only send messages to people using the same client. I might like gmail, but if my boss liked outlook I&amp;rsquo;d have to use that. The fragmented system would cause email to have fraction of the value. If that seems hard to imagine, consider how many instant messaging platforms there are. None of these platforms exchange messages between themselves, despite large investments. The value of communication technology lies in network effects, so it seems strange that this continues to be the case.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>